<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Graphical Data Apps</title>
        <link>https://alleetanner.github.io/graphical-data-apps/</link>
        <description>Graphical Data Apps</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2023 00:00:00 &#43;0100</lastBuildDate>
            <atom:link href="https://alleetanner.github.io/graphical-data-apps/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <item>
    <title>• Working with data</title>
    <link>https://alleetanner.github.io/graphical-data-apps/posts/03data/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2023 00:00:00 &#43;0100</pubDate>
    <author>Alastair Tanner</author>
    <guid>https://alleetanner.github.io/graphical-data-apps/posts/03data/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Section title  bullet1 bullt2  Normal text body.
Warning   Warning1 Warning2     Info   Info1 Info2    
Another section blahfdajkfhu aefuibahj rwefyugr
code goes herer next setion blakfahuir wrafguighbarg
Exercise Questions  a question box
 q1 q2     ]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>• First steps</title>
    <link>https://alleetanner.github.io/graphical-data-apps/posts/02streamlit_intro/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2023 00:00:00 &#43;0100</pubDate>
    <author>Alastair Tanner</author>
    <guid>https://alleetanner.github.io/graphical-data-apps/posts/02streamlit_intro/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Arranging the Jupyter Lab tab If you followed the previous page, you should have a Jupyter Lab session open in a tab in your browser. In the Jupyter Lab file navigator to the left, create a new folder to work in, and move into it. We are going to have two panes open: one Python file, and one Terminal. You can open these either from the launch screen (with icons), or from the menu bar (in the Jupyter Lab tab menu, not the browser menu!]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>∙ Requirements and set up</title>
    <link>https://alleetanner.github.io/graphical-data-apps/posts/01requirements/</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2023 00:00:00 &#43;0100</pubDate>
    <author>Alastair Tanner</author>
    <guid>https://alleetanner.github.io/graphical-data-apps/posts/01requirements/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Glossary  The words library, module and package are often used interchangeably, and they mean very similar things; it is entirely natural to be confused by this!
 Library : a collection of python files that expand the ability of python, using the import command. These are like accessories or modifications, typically giving you access to powerful, professional functions and classes written by collaborations of expert coders.  A library can be standard (it comes built into python), for example time or math, or 3rd party, so, written by people outside of the core Python developers, and as such will need to be installed using a package manager.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>• Why build data apps?</title>
    <link>https://alleetanner.github.io/graphical-data-apps/posts/00intro/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2023 00:00:00 &#43;0100</pubDate>
    <author>Alastair Tanner</author>
    <guid>https://alleetanner.github.io/graphical-data-apps/posts/00intro/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[What are data apps? A data app is a type of app that allows exploration of a dataset without requiring specific technical skills, and in generating visualisations. A data app can also be a web app, if it is deployed to the internet so that others can use it through a web browser. In any case, the general goals of any data is is to:
 bridge technical aspects of working with data, making analysis more accessible, create visualisations, which can provide insights which might remain hidden in the data, promote exploration, prototyping, and hypothesis development, facilitate collaboration, and the sharing of visualisations and datasets, educate users on what methods are being applied.]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
